Software Engineer

SUMMARY

I am a full stack software engineer with a passion for collaborative tools, distributed systems, and cloud computing. I design, implement, and scale distributed systems and have multiple years of experience building software with a proficiency in Ruby, Rails, Node, JavaScript, Git, Linux, and RESTful APIs.

EXPERIENCE

SpaceCraft (https://spacecraft-repl.github.io/)

Co-Creator

Houston, TX

October 2018 - Present

- Co-created and deployed an open-source, real-time, collaborative REPL.
- Built a network architecture that scales allows multiple users to collaborate in a private session.
- Developed real-time synchronization for input/output for collaborating users.
- Created a container architecture to isolate user sessions, prevent malicious attacks, and limit session resources.
- Implemented a reverse proxy to scale the application to dozens of concurrent users and sessions.
- Wrote a detailed case study (https://spacecraft-repl.github.io/whitepaper).

Client Manager

CareCloud

Miami, FL

December 2015 - April 2017

- Oversaw and managed revenue cycle management of 18-26 medical practices.
- Consulted on RCM and industry best practices. Raised revenue on insurance collections by up to 20% for accounts.
- Responsible for building effective relationships with CareCloud clients resulting in high-levels of client satisfaction, retention and practice improvement.

RECENT PROJECTS

Lander

https://github.com/spacecraft-repl/lander

- A Ruby gem that allows developers to easily log data structures for solving coding challenges.
- Currently supports logging for arrays with pointers, linked lists, and trees.

EXTRACURRICULAR

Technical Blog Writer

February 2018 - Present

Currently wrote 4 articles about various software engineering topics with ~2400

SKILLS & LANGUAGES

Back-End: Node, Express, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs

Front-End: JavaScript, React/Redux, HTML/CSS

Other: Git, Linux, Docker, WebSockets, Distributed Systems, Heroku

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Austin

Austin, TX, September 2010 - May 2015

B.S. in Physics